(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-12T13:47:55.293084",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
跳ねた 跳ねた 僕は跳ねた
I bounced, I bounced, I bounced away,
小学生みたいに
like an elementary schooler,
雨上がりの夜に跳ねた
bounding into the post-rain night,
覗き見みたいに
like taking a peek.
見ていたふりした
Pretending I was just watching,
朝を待っていた
waiting for the morning to come.
夜に逃げただけ
I just ran away into the night,
朝を待っていた
waiting for the morning.
跳ねた 跳ねた 君も跳ねた
You bounced, you bounced, you bounced away too,
小学生みたいに
like an elementary schooler,
三日月の上で跳ねた
bounding on top of the crescent moon,
雨模様みたいに
like rainy weather.
忘れたふりした
Pretending I forgot all about it,
それはつまり
that means—
夜に逃げただけ
I just ran away into the night.
どこへ行こう どこへ行こう
Where should I go? Where should I go?
ここにいようとして
Trying to stay right here...
逃げるよ 逃げるよ
I'll run away, I'll run away,
あと少しだけ
just a little bit more.
消えた 消えた 君が消えた
You disappeared, you disappeared, you vanished away,
真っ暗闇みたいに
like pitch darkness.
にわか雨の音も消えた
The sound of the sudden rain faded away,
さよなら言うように
As if saying goodbye.
きこえたふりして
Pretending I heard it,
君の言う通り
Just as you said.
夜に逃げただけ
Just running away into the night.
どこへ行こう
Where should I go?
ここに居ようとしている？
Are you trying to stay here?
逃げても
Even if I run away,
音はもうしなくて
There's no sound left anymore.
雨になって何分か後に行く
I'll become the rain and go a few minutes later.
今泣いて何分か後に行く
Crying now, I'll go a few minutes later.
今泣いて何分か後の自分
Myself a few minutes later, crying now.
今泣いて何分か後に行く
Crying now, I'll go a few minutes later.
今泣いて何年か後の自分
Myself a few years later, crying now.
行けるよ
We can go.
どこへ行こうとして
Where are we trying to go?
イメージしよう 自分がもう
Let's imagine ourselves already...
雨になって何分か後に行く
Becoming the rain and going a few minutes later.
今泣いて何分か後に行く
Crying now, going a few minutes later.
今泣いて何年か後の自分
Myself a few years later, crying now.
今泣いて何分か後に行く
Crying now, going a few minutes later.
今泣いて何年か後の自分
Myself a few years later, crying now.
笑っていたいんだろう
You want to be smiling, don't you?
はーい、ということで！
Alright, with that said!
ほら、アコースティックライブ始まりました！
Look, the acoustic live has begun!
という こと でね、楽しんでいただけてますかね。
So, I hope you're enjoying it.
いや、1曲目は嫉妬に始まったかと思いきや、
Wait, you'd think the first song started with jealousy,
元気にいく夜の踊り子で、わあ、始めさせていただきました！
but it was energetic 'Night Dancer', we started with a wow!
最高でした！最高だった！
It was amazing! It was awesome!
ちょっと気持ちよくなりすぎて、なんか、最後間違えちゃった。
I got a bit too carried away and made a mistake at the end.
危うく生き延びられませんでしたけどね。はい、失礼いたしましたということで。
Almost didn't survive there. Yes, my apologies.
え、本日一緒に歌ってくださるメンバーがあと2人いるので、全員で呼んじゃいたいと思います！どうぞ！
Now, there are two more members singing with us today, so let's call them all out! Go ahead!
いぇーい！いぇーい！
Yay! Yay!
いや、盛り上がりすぎじゃない！？盛り上がりすぎだよ！カメラ目線カメラ目線！
Isn't this too hyped?! It's too hyped! Camera angle, camera angle!
いや、でもこだわってましたね、カメラワークもね。MVっぽい感じでね。
Well, but they were particular about the camerawork too. Giving it an MV-like feel.
やってくださった人柄がすごいこだわってやってくださって、チェイス、チェイス、チェイス！
The people who did it were very particular, chase, chase, chase!
やらせていただきました！素晴らしい！まずは…
We did it! Wonderful! So, first...
今日一緒に歌っていただく皆さん、自己紹介をお願いしたいと思います！ではあずきから！
We'd like everyone singing with us today to introduce themselves! Starting with AZKi!
はーい！こんこんこんこん、あずき！右手にマイク、左手に地図、あなたのハートを狙い撃ち！あずきです！よろしくお願いします！
Hi! Con-con-con-con, AZKi! Microphone in right hand, map in left, sniping right into your heart! I'm AZKi! Nice to meet you!
第2回に引き続き！ありがとうございます！
Continuing for the 2nd time! Thank you so much!
第2回いつあるんですかってね、あずきがちょいちょい聞いててさ。でもなんかもう一回やろうっていう…
AZKi kept asking when the 2nd time would be. But you know, wanting to do it once more...
勇気にね、本当につながったんで、感謝しております。ありがとうございます！お願いします！
truly gave us the courage, so we are grateful. Thank you! Please!
お願いしまーす！
Thank you!
そして常闇トワ様！
And Tokoyami Towa-sama!
はい！えー、こうやっぴ！ホロライブの、ホロライブ4期生…
Yes! Um, Koyappi! Hololive's, Hololive 4th Gen...
ここ大事だから！ややこしいやつ来た。
This part is important! A complicated one came.
ホロライブの、えっと、常闇トワ様です！さあ、よろしくお願いいたします！
Hololive's, um, Tokoyami Towa-sama! Well, nice to meet you!
お願いしまーす！トワ様様！
Thank you! Towa-sama-sama!
うれしい！まぶしっと思ってますので、勝手にね。
I'm so happy! It's dazzling, so on my own accord.
温度感違いますけど大丈夫？
The temperature feels different, is that okay?
どっかどっかで一緒に歌えるのすごい嬉しいです よろしくお願いします
I'm so glad we get to sing together! Looking forward to it!
そしてなんと
And what's more,
今日小音のために インドネシアから日本に来てくれた
coming all the way from Indonesia to Japan just for today—
コーバ！
Kobo!
はい、こぼこぼこぼこぼ！ないると、your service, let me be your sun to shine your day!
Hi! Kobo Kobo Kobo Kobo! Nairu is at your service, let me be your sun to shine your day!
こぼかないる連ちゃんおんりすからホロライブ、ホロヒーロー！よろしくお願いします！
Kobo kanaeru continuous stream from Hololive, HoloHero! Nice to meet you!
ホロヒーロー！
HoloHero!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
てんきゅーまっしゅ！
Thank you very much!
しゃーましゃーま
Shama shama!
どういたしましてって言うんだよ
You're supposed to say 'you're welcome'!
そうそうそう！てんきゅーまっしゅ、本当によろしくお願いします！
Right right right! Thank you so much, really looking forward to it!
もう一曲目からね、一緒に歌わせてもらいましたけど
We got to sing together right from the first song,
この後もよろしくお願いします！
and we look forward to the rest of the show too!
よろしくお願いします！
Looking forward to it!
始まる前、緊張するって言ってて
Before it started, she was saying she was so nervous—
めちゃ自信ある
I'm super confident!
オーケー！オーケー、かっこいいホロヒーロー！
Okay! Okay, cool HoloHero!
イエーイ！かっこいい！ベリークール！
Yay! Cool! Very cool!
では、続きまして、声も歌声が大好きな二コたん！
Now, moving on, Nico-tan, whose singing voice we all love!
やったー！二コたんが来た！
Yay! Nico-tan is here!
ホロライブデバイオスプロ、ふろ...？
Hololive Dev_is pro, fro...?
ほら、ご覧あれ、我が家の二コです。二コたん、だよ！
Look, behold, this is our Nico. It's Nico-tan!
ここ最近ちょっと自己紹介が変わったりしてさ。ちょっと緊張してますよね、今日。
Lately my self-introduction has changed a bit. I'm pretty nervous today.
もう一曲歌ったしね。なんか歌うと脳が切り替わっちゃって。あ、そうなの？しゃべれなくなるんだよね。
We already sang a song, right? When you sing, your brain switches over. Ah, really? You get unable to talk.
あ、今歌のモードになってるか。そう、今日はもうしゃべれません。
Ah, I'm in singing mode now. Right, today I can't talk anymore.
どうしてなんですか？
Why is that?
いや、本当に呼んでくれてありがとうございます！こちらこそ！
No, thank you so much for inviting me! Likewise!
一緒に歌えるのすごい嬉しくて。
I'm so happy we get to sing together.
楽しみにしてました！
I was looking forward to it!
行きましょう！
Let's go!
楽しみにしております！
We're looking forward to it!
そして、え、ホロライブ6期生、ホロックスの沙花叉クロヱだよ！
And, um, Hololive 6th Gen, HoloX's Sakamata Chloe!
ということで、第2回もこうして皆さんに来ていただいたことで開催できてとっても嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします！
So, I'm so happy we were able to hold the 2nd installment with everyone coming here. Thank you so much!
そして、今日ピアノは、前回に引き続きウイングさんに
And today, the piano is once again being played by Wing-san,
引いていただきますよ！
playing for us!
なになにこれ？学校みたい。あ、これ、ジャパニーズスクール！
What's this? Like a school. Ah, this is Japanese school!
おそいですかい？
Is it slow?
そうなんです。あ、じゃあもう一回！
That's right. Ah, then one more time!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ここも体験できた！やっと始まった、やっと始まりました。
I got to experience this too! It finally started, it finally started.
そして、今回もですね、こちら完全生3Dライブということで、最初から最後まで生で全部お届いたしますので、
And this time too, this is a completely live 3D concert, bringing everything to you live from start to finish,
優しい目でで見守ってください！
so please watch over us with kind eyes!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you!
ハッシュタグは、こちらホロアコースティックライブとなっております！
The hashtag is #holoAcousticLive!
そして、えっとここには書いてないんですけども、白衣小ゆり重、超重大告知というハッシュタグもありまして、本日は途中で告知もありますので、
And, um, it's not written here, but there's also a hashtag for Kobo Kanaeru's super major announcement, and we have announcements midway today as well,
ぜひ皆さん最後まで見ていってください！
so everyone please stay tuned until the very end!
では、ここからはちょっと二人、二人で順番に歌っていくしっとりコーナーに行こうかなと思います。
Now, from here, we're going into a mellow corner where the two of you will take turns singing.
最初に一緒に歌ってくれるのは？
Who's singing together first?
ガチャ！
Gacha!
ガチャで当たったのはあずき！
The one who won the gacha is AZKi!
やったー！
Yay!
それでは歌いたいと思います。他の皆さんはちょっとゆっくりしててください。私たちはしゃべるためだけに連れてこられたわけじゃありません。
Now then, we'd like to sing. Everyone else, please relax. We weren't brought here just to talk, haha.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
ということで今日は、インオータムということでですね、
So today is 'In Autumn',
秋っぽい曲を、いいですね。
so we gathered some autumn-like songs—sounds nice.
あてめましたよ。
We collected them.
いや、これは一緒に歌いたかった。
Man, I really wanted to sing this together.
そう、あずあずが言ってくれて。
Yeah, Azu-azu suggested it.
歌うことになって。そうなんです。超ハッピー！超ハッピーです。はい。選曲させていただきました。歌わせてもらいます。はい。ではではちょっとタイトルコールお願いしちゃいましょうかね。それでは聴いてください。「暁の車」
So we ended up singing it. That's right. Super happy! Super happy. Yep, I selected the songs and got to sing it. Yes. Now then, shall we ask for the title call? Please listen to 'Akatsuki no Kuruma'.
風さそう木陰に蹲って泣いてる
Weeping, crouched in the shade where the wind invites...
やさしい光に 包まれて泣いた
Enfolded in a gentle light, I wept,
だろう 身も知らぬ私を 私が見ていた
As if watching over a stranger that was myself.
行く人の調べを奏でるギターから
From the guitar playing a melody for those who depart,
この人の嘆きに 星は落ちて
Stars fall upon this person's lamentations.
行かないで どんなに叫んでも
"Don't go, no matter how much I cry out,"
オレンジの花びらのように静かに揺れるだけ
It merely sways quietly like orange petals.
柔らかな日々に残された
Left behind in those gentle days,
手のひらの希望を隠して
Hiding the hope in the palm of my hand,
遠くシエへのさよならつむぐ
Plucking a farewell to eternity far away.
やさしい手にすがる 子供の心を
Clinging to gentle hands, a child's heart
燃え盛る車は 振り払い進む
Shakes off the blazing chariot and moves forward.
行く人の嘆きを奏でるギターから
From the guitar playing a lament for those who depart,
胸の糸激しくかき鳴らして
Strumming the strings of my heart passionately.
赤き闇に染まない白さで
With a purity untainted by crimson darkness,
オレンジの花びら揺れてた夏の陰に
In the shade of summer where orange petals swayed.
行かないで どんなに日々を無くしても
"Don't go, no matter what days we lose,"
赤く染めた歌ははるか超えてゆく
Songs dyed in crimson reach far beyond.
思い出を焼き尽くして進む大地に
Upon the earth we advance, burning away memories,
懐かしく芽吹いていくものがあるの
Something begins to sprout with nostalgia.
暁の車を見送って
Seeing off the chariot of dawn,
オレンジの花びら揺れてる今もどこかで
Orange petals are still swaying somewhere now.
いつか見た穏やかな夜をもう一度手にするまで
Until once again I hold in my hands the peaceful night,
消さないで灯火
Do not extinguish the lamplight.
車は回るよ
The wheel keeps turning.
ああ あんなにさ
Ah, after all that,
この不愛嬌でした世界に落とされたんだ
I was dropped into this unfriendly world.
ふざけんなっつってさ こんなものの
"Don't mess with me," I said, for something
ために生まれたんじゃない
like this, I wasn't born for it.
とっくに埋もれる足取り
Footsteps long since buried,
倒れそうになるのを
about to collapse,
この鎖が許さない
these chains won't forgive me.
心は愛嬌私じゃなくて
My heart isn't charming,
あなたの感覚だけが散らばって
only your sensations are scattered around.
私はまだ上手に片付けられずに
I'm still unable to tidy them away neatly.
ああ あんなにさ
Ah, after all that,
この不愛嬌でした世界に落とされたんだ
I was dropped into this unfriendly world.
ふざけんなっつってさ こんなものの
"Don't mess with me," I said, for something
ために生まれたんじゃない
like this, I wasn't born for it.
理由はもっと喋り続けて
Give me a reason, keep talking to me
私がい眠れるまで
until I can fall asleep.
効かない薬ばっかり取っ払ってるけど
I keep taking ineffective pills, but
ここにコンプレックスもないのにいったい何を信じれば
what on earth should I believe in when there's no complex here?
ああ あんなにさ
Ah, after all that,
悲しい音は背中に詰め込んで
stuffing sad sounds into my back.
バカげた理想もこんな重荷じゃ
Even absurd ideals are such a burden
どこにもい場所なんてない
that there's nowhere left for me to belong.
不愉快に冷たい壁とか
Unpleasantly cold walls and such,
次は誰に弱さを許す？
who will you allow your weakness to next?
終わりになど手を伸ばさないであなたなら救い出して
Don't reach out for the end, if it's you, rescue me
私を静寂から
from the silence.
時間は痛みを加速させてく
Time accelerates the pain.
ああ あんなにさ
Ah, after all that,
この不愛嬌でした世界に落とされたんだ
I was dropped into this unfriendly world.
ふざけんなっつってさ こんなものの
"Don't mess with me," I said, for something
ために生まれたんじゃない
like this, I wasn't born for it.
ああ あんなにさ
Ah, after all that,
悲しい音は背中に詰め込んで
stuffing sad sounds into my back.
バカげた理想もこんな重荷じゃ
Even absurd ideals are such a burden
どこにもい場所なんてない
that there's nowhere left for me to belong.
あとはリボン結んであなたなら救い出して
Tie the ribbon, if it's you, rescue me...
夕陽 並木道 二人
Sunset, a tree-lined path, the two of us...
つぶやく君の言葉 あの小さな プラネタリウム
murmuring your words into that small planetarium,
また行きたいねと 微笑む
smiling as you say, "Let's go again."
この空のどこかに君はいるんだろ
You must be somewhere in this sky.
付き合い始めの頃に よく二人で行ったね
When we first started dating, we often went together.
この公園で見つけた あの星座なんだっけ覚えている？
In this park we found... what constellation was that? Do you remember?
会えなくても記憶をたどって
Even if I can't meet you, I retrace my memories,
同じ幸せを見たいんだ
wanting to see that same happiness.
あの香りとともに花火がぱっと開く
Along with that scent, fireworks burst open in a flash.
行きたいよ 君のところへ 今すぐ駆け出して行きたいよ
I want to go to your place, rushing over right now.
真っ暗で何も見えない 怖くても大丈夫
In pitch darkness where nothing can be seen, even if I'm scared, it's okay.
数え切れない星空が 今もすぐここにあるんだよ
The countless starry sky is right here even now.
叶わないよ おかしきみと見た綺麗なお空だったから
It won't come true, because it was such a beautiful sky we saw together.
あの道まで響く靴音が耳にのこる
The sound of footsteps echoing all the way to that path remains in my ears.
大きな自分の影を見つめて想うのでしょう
Staring at my large shadow, I must be thinking.
ちっとも変わらないはずなのに 切ない気持ちふくらんでく
Even though nothing should have changed at all, painful feelings swell up.
どんなに思っていても 君はもういない
No matter how much I think of you, you're no longer here.
行きたいよ 君のそばに 小さくても 小さくても 一番に君が好きだよ 強くいられる
I want to go to your side, even if it's small, you're the one I love most, so I can be strong.
願いを流れ星に そっととなえてみたけれど 泣かないよ 届くだろう きれいな空に
I tried softly reciting a wish upon a shooting star. I won't cry, it will reach that beautiful sky.
会えなくても記憶をたどって 同じ幸せを見たいんだ
Even if I can't meet you, I retrace my memories, wanting to see that same happiness.
願いを流れ星に そっととなえてみたけれど 泣かないよ 届かないよ
I tried softly reciting a wish upon a shooting star. I won't cry... it won't reach you...
届くだろう 綺麗な空に...
it will reach... the beautiful sky...
会えなくても記憶をたどって 同じ幸せを見たいんだ
Even if I can't meet you, I retrace my memories, wanting to see that same happiness.
あの香りとともに花火がぱっと開く
Along with that scent, fireworks burst open in a flash.
行きたいよ 君のところへ 小さな手を握り締めて
I want to go to your place, grasping your little hand tightly.
泣きたいよ それはそれは綺麗な空だった
I want to cry, that was, that was a beautiful sky.
願いを流れ星に そっととなえてみたけれど 泣かないよ 届かないよ 思いをこの空に
I tried softly reciting a wish upon a shooting star. I won't cry, my feelings won't reach... into this sky.
ずっと一緒にいた
We were always together,
二人で歩いた一本道
walking down a single path together.
二つに分かれて
splitting into two,
別々の方歩いてく
walking separate ways.
寂しさで溢れたこの胸抱えて
Holding this chest overflowing with loneliness,
今にも泣き出しそうな空見上げて
looking up at the sky that might start crying at any moment...
あなたを想った
I thought of you.
君がいない夜だって そうno more cry もう泣かないよ
Even on nights when you're not here, yes, no more cry, I won't cry anymore.
がんばっているからねって 強くなるからねって
Saying "I'm doing my best, I'll grow stronger,"
君も見ているだろう この消えそうな三日月
You must be looking at this fading crescent moon too.
つながっているからねって 愛しているからねって
Saying "We're connected," saying "I love you,"
冷えきった手を 一人で温める日々
Days when I warm my chilled hands all by myself,
君の温もり 恋しくて恋しくて
longing, so longing for your warmth.
どれだけ電話で「好き」と言われたって
No matter how many times you said "I love you" over the phone,
君によりかかることはできない
I cannot lean on you.
涙をぬぐった
I wiped away my tears...
君によりかかることはできない
I cannot lean on you.
涙をぬぐった
I wiped away my tears.
君がいない夜だって そうno more cry もう泣かないよ
Even on nights when you're not here, yes, no more cry, I won't cry anymore.
がんばっているからねって 強くなるからねって
Saying "I'm doing my best, I'll grow stronger,"
君も見ているだろう この消えそうな三日月
You must be looking at this fading crescent moon too.
今度いつ会えるんだろう
When will we be able to meet next?
それまでの電池は
Until then, the battery...
抱きしめながら言った あなたの「愛してる」の一言
Holding me close, you said that single word, "I love you."
君がいない夜だって そうno more cry もう泣かないよ
Even on nights when you're not here, yes, no more cry, I won't cry anymore.
がんばっているからねって 強くなるからねって
Saying "I'm doing my best, I'll grow stronger,"
君も見ているだろう この消えそうな三日月
You must be looking at this fading crescent moon too.
つながっているからねって 愛しているからねって
Saying "We're connected," saying "I love you,"
三日月日に手を伸ばした 君に届けこの想い
I reached my hand out to the crescent moon, hoping this feeling reaches you.
君に届け この想い
Hoping this feeling reaches you.
はい、ということで4曲続けて二人ずつお届けさせていただきました！皆さん、
Yes, with that, we've delivered four songs in pairs! Everyone,
めっちゃ良くないですか！？最高じゃないですか！
isn't this amazing?! Isn't this the best?!
はーい！
Yeah!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
では、ちょっと2曲目から振り返ってみようかと思うんですけど、
Now then, we'd like to look back starting from the second song,
まずはAZKiと「アズキ色の車」！
but first, AZKi and "Azuki-iro no Kuruma"!
いや、
Man,
素晴らしかったですね。
that was truly wonderful.
この曲、あずきちが歌えたのめっちゃ嬉しいです。
I'm so happy Azuki-chan got to sing this song.
え、今夜も？
Eh, tonight too?
え、嬉しい！
Eh, I'm so happy!
でも、こんな秋にも、挟まれると
But being sandwiched in such autumn too...
なんか、ちょっと（笑）
It's kind of...
間違って、なんかテンパっちゃった。すみません、すみません。
I got flustered by mistake. Sorry, sorry!
めちゃくちゃピアノも素敵で。
The piano was so wonderful too.
いや、本当にね、この曲、
Yeah, really, this song...
しーちゃんでしたね。
it was Shii-chan.
あの「ギターある」って言うから、本当ギターが凄い鳴る曲なんですけど、
She said "there's a guitar," so it's a song where the guitar really resonates,
ピアノオンリーになると「こういう感じなんだな」って。
but with just piano, it's like "Ah, so this is what it feels like."
いや、良かったです。一人でやらせていただきました。ありがとうございました。
Yeah, it was great. I got to perform it alone. Thank you very much!
はい、ありがとうございます。
Yes, thank you.
なんか真ん中緊張する！
Man, standing in the middle is so nerve-wracking!
めっちゃ真ん中緊張する！
Standing right in the middle is so nerve-wracking!
とわ様、どうぞ。
Towa-sama, go ahead.
今夜ねもね、これトワ様の声でも再生されてたもん！
Tonight too, you know, this was even played back in Towa-sama's voice!
あいすぎ！
It fits too well!
うん。
Yeah.
え、歌えてたかな？
Eh, did I sing it right?
え、もう超、
Eh, like, super—
意外と緊張しちゃったんだけど。
I was surprisingly nervous though.
いやだ、ちょっと。
Oh no, wait.
え、めっちゃ良かった！
Eh, it was amazing!
コヨリが一生緊張してたんで。
Because Koyori was nervous the whole time.
あ、そうなの？
Ah, is that so?
すごいカタカタ。
Trembling so much.
え、嘘！
Eh, no way!
リハの方がゆっくりしてましたね。
Well, rehearsal was more relaxed.
一応この歌詞見やるんですよ、
You look at these lyrics, you know,
この歌いながら。
while singing this.
はいはいはい。
Right, right, right.
で、なんか「今夜の」パートの歌詞が、
And like, the lyrics for the "Koyoi no" part,
とんでもないことになってて、
became something unbelievable,
なんて言えばいいんだろ、あれ？
how should I put it, what is that?
「伸ばし」とか「おーおーおー」って、「お」全部
"Nobashi" or "O-o-o", saying "O", all...
そうそう、全部書いてあるの。全部文字に表すんですよ。
That's right, it's all written down. It's all expressed in letters.
英語の部分とかも全部カタカナにして、
Even the English parts were all put in katakana,
ちょっとね「ひどいな」って思ったから、
and well, I thought "that's awful,"
「アイアンガッチャーイ」って書いてあったの。
so I wrote "Iron Gatchaa-i".
そう、ガッチャイ（笑）
Yeah, Gatcha-i.
その時の時はだいぶ爆笑したけど、ちゃんと歌えてよかったよ。
I laughed a lot at that time, but I'm glad I could sing it properly.
よかった。
I'm glad.
本当すいませんでした。
I'm really sorry.
コヨリのせいでね。
All because of Koyori.
はい、そしてコボとね、「プラネタリウム」！
Yes, and Kobo and "Planetarium"!
プラネタリウム、どういうの？
"Planetarium", what's it like?
新しい、いやいやいや、新しい。
New— no, no, no, new.
え？覚えたの？
Eh? You memorized it?
初めて、ファースト、
For the first time, first—
すごい！
Amazing!
めっちゃ素敵な曲だ。
Such a wonderful song.
めっちゃ早く覚えた。
I memorized it super fast.
覚えた？
You memorized it?
そうそう、めっちゃ早く覚えた。
Yeah, yeah, I memorized it super fast.
コボズボイスにぴったりに。
It fits Kobo's voice perfectly.
あ、ぴったり。
Ah, perfectly.
あ、そっか、最後のハーモニー頑張ってくれたんですって！
Ah, right, you worked hard on the final harmony!
すごい素敵なハーモニーだった。
It was such a wonderful harmony.
ありがとう、テル、任せ？
Thank you, Tellu, trust me?
ハーモニーグッド。ソンド？
Harmony good. Sound?
オッケー、グッド。それは、なんかインプロフィセーション。
Okay, good. That was, like, improvisation.
ん？インプロフィセーション？
Hmm? Improvisation?
インプロフィセーションは？
What is improvisation?
インプロフィセーション、よかったかな？よかった。
Improvisation, was it good? It was good.
よかった、めっちゃバグス。
It was great, super bugs.
イェーイ、めっちゃいい、めっちゃバグス、バグス？
Yeah! Super good, super bugs, bugs?
ワグス、イェーイ、バグス！
Wagus, yeah, bugs!
あとで教えてもらおう。
I'll have you teach me later.
そして、ニコタンとね、月を
And, with Nico-tan, "Tsuki o"
歌わせてもらいました、3つ、めっちゃぴったり。
we got to sing it, three of them fit so well.
いや、良かったです。
Yeah, it was great.
ニコタンもリハまでなんか、楽しく歌えてるだけだったんですけど、
Nico-tan too, until rehearsal, she was just singing happily,
立った瞬間緊張しちゃって。
but the moment she stood up, she got nervous.
皆さんもそうだと思うんですけど。
I think everyone feels the same way.
本当だよな。
That's so true.
とても泣かせ、
Really making us cry...
ですか？良かったです。
Is that so? I'm glad.
ここに立ち続けてるこよ先輩もなんかすごいなと思って、
And Koyori-senpai standing here the whole time is amazing too,
顔を合わせた瞬間ちょっと泣き虫になっちゃって。
the moment we locked eyes, I almost became a crybaby.
ちょっとまたウルトしちゃって。
And got emotional again.
ウルトしちゃった？大変だった。
Got emotional? It was tough.
なんか、こよが勝手にこの曲、なんかニコタンのこと色々考えちゃって、
Koyori arbitrarily thought about various things regarding Nico-tan for this song,
なんか、すごいね、思い浮かべながら、なんかね、大事に歌わせてもらいました。
and, like, while imagining things, we got to sing it preciously.
ニコタンも実は結構思い出
Nico-tan actually had a lot of memories...
色々思い出し考えてました。いや、マジか、そういうこと！？
thought about various things. Wait, seriously, is that so?!
すごいよ、先輩！
That's amazing, senpai!
すごい、ちょっとね、いろんな意味でもすごく
Well, amazing, in various ways, it was really...
あってるし、声にも合ってるしね。
fits, and matches your voice too.
ありがとうございます。最高でした。みんなに届けられて良かったです。
Thank you. It was the best. I'm glad it reached everyone.
お疲れ様！
Good job!
お疲れ様！お疲れ様！
Good job! Good job!
この曲で終わっちゃうの？
Is it ending with this song?
いや、そうですね、ちょっと今回は、
Yeah, that's right, this time,
今日はちょっと重大告知もあるので、全部お邪魔しました。
today there's also a major announcement, so we joined in on everything.
やっと追ってると、重いよ。
Following along all this time is heavy.
ありがとうございます。いや、それででも楽しかったけど緊張ししまいました。
Thank you. Well, even so it was fun, but I got nervous.
それでは、この後はですね、ちょっとみんなと特別なメドレーを歌いたいと思います。
Now then, after this, we'd like to sing a special medley with everyone.
まだあるんですか？
There's more?
まだまだありますよ！
There's still plenty!
続いてはですね、やっぱちょっとね、小夜ずっといるのもなみたいな気持ちがあって、
Next up, feeling like Koyori has been here the whole time,
みんなのシャッフルを聞きたかったので、オリジナル曲をスペシャルシャッフルメドレーさせていただきます！
we wanted to hear everyone's shuffles, so we're going to do a special shuffle medley of original songs!
それでは、最初に歌っていただく、AZAZとニコタンを残して、
So first, leaving AZAZ and Nico-tan to sing,
ちょっとあとの3人はお供しましょうか。
the other three will step aside for a bit.
暖かいときに
When it's warm...
息をしている
I am breathing,
だから生きている
that is why I'm alive.
何度もずっと言葉を尽くしてきたんだ
Over and over, I poured my words into them.
息をしている
I am breathing,
ように見えている 青が染まる私にとってのなにか
or so it seems, in this blue-dyed world of mine.
孤独が孤独をしている
Loneliness is being lonely;
ここはいつも変わらずに
this place always remains unchanged,
せかし続ける ボタンひとつのいのち
hurrying along a life with just the push of a button.
最後までわたしのこと覚えててくれるの
Will you remember me until the very end?
消えてしまいそうなの 分かってよ 分かってよね
It feels like I'm going to fade away—please understand, won't you?
本当んとこなの いずれは卒業をするんでしょう
Is it really true? Will I graduate someday?
日常に戻ったら私はいなくなるの
If I return to everyday life, will I disappear?
命のような夢を見てるよ またね バイバイ
Dreaming a dream like life itself... See you, bye-bye.
自信なんてなかった ひとりだってよかった
I had no confidence, I was fine being alone.
プライドに隠れて
Hiding behind my pride,
誰かの視線 気になってばかりで閉じこもってた
I cared too much about everyone's gaze and shut myself away.
綺麗だなんて思えなくて 笑えなかったんだ
I couldn't think it was beautiful, and I couldn't smile.
涙でねじった画面の向こう 不意に溶けた心
Beyond the screen twisted by tears, my heart suddenly melted.
触れてくれた声 君のおかげで笑えたよ
The voice that reached out to me—thanks to you, I was able to smile.
その言葉がずっと この胸を灯す
Those words will forever light up this chest.
たった一つの光
Just a single light.
Hold on! Take me higher!
消えそうな声をふたりに変えて
Changing our fading voices into two,
弱さ抱きしめながら
embracing our weakness,
凍えて叫ぶように燃やす炎
a flame burning as we cry out while freezing.
炎
Flames...
Hold on! Take me higher!
君の明日を照らしたい
I want to illuminate your tomorrow.
黙ってうつむいて 空の色さえ知らない
Silent and looking down, I didn't even know the color of the sky—
私の
the me who knew nothing.
声であなたが笑った あの日 から世界はまぶしくて
With your voice, you smiled; ever since that day, the world has been so dazzling.
私は私を好きになって
I've come to like myself,
なくさないように息をする
breathing so as not to lose it.
有象無象 人の成り
Phantoms and realities, human shapes,
虚勢 心象 人外 物怪みたいだ
false bravado, inner images, monsters.
虚心坦懐 命宿し
An open mind, harboring life,
あとはぱっぱらっぱな中身なき人間
and the rest is just empty, hollow humans.
寄せる期待 不平等な人生
Building expectations, an unfair life,
才能もない 大乗非日常が
with no talent, a grand extraordinary life
怨親平等に没個性
equalizes grudge and affection, losing individuality.
辿る記憶 僕に
Memories I trace, leaving me
居場所なんてないから
with no place to belong,
夢の狭間で泣いていないで
don't cry in the narrow gaps of dreams.
どんな顔すればいいか わかってる
I know what kind of face I should make,
だけどまだ応えてくれよ
but still, answer me.
闇を穿って 闇を穿って
Pierce the darkness, pierce the darkness,
夜の帳が下りたら合図だ
when the veil of night falls, that's the signal.
相対して 巡る環状戦
Facing each other, a circular battle,
戯言などは吐き捨ていけと
spitting out idle words and moving on,
まだ止めないで まだ止めないで
don't stop yet, don't stop yet,
誰よりも煌く在る 街に生まれしこの正体を
the true identity born in this town, shining brighter than anyone.
寄せる期待 不平等な人生
Building expectations, an unfair life,
才能もない 大乗非日常が
with no talent, a grand extraordinary life
怨親平等に没個性
equalizes grudge and affection, losing individuality.
辿る記憶 僕に
Memories I trace, leaving me
居場所なんてないから
with no place to belong,
夢の狭間で泣いていないで
don't cry in the narrow gaps of dreams.
I recognize the face staring back at me today
I guess it's time to change
When I'm down, if I like myself, I don't need someone else
'Cause daily juice boosts grace, energy restores sense
You can catch me up, I'm the key, I can't move on in a heartbeat
Second, slick is looking like, slick is looking like me
Every night, I'm just moving to the rhythm of a different light
Say goodbye 'cause I'm more alive than the girl you met tonight
Switch it up, ooh ooh ooh
I just want to feel my heart, just feel my heart, though boom boom boom
Every time I'm heading out of who I was, as far as I'm just switching it up again
あの子になんてやめてあたしにすればいいのに!
Forget about her and choose me instead!
はたから見てもなおわかるのは あの子が君を好きじゃないこと
Even from afar, it's obvious she doesn't like you,
それでも側にいたい気持ちも 理解できちゃうから困ってる
yet I understand wanting to stay by your side, which is troublesome.
あたしの気持ちを噂で流しちゃう? 君の耳元にいつか届くように
Should I spread rumors of my feelings? So they eventually reach your ears.
あの子になんてやめてあたしにすればいいのに! 終電だって逃すのに
Forget about her and choose me instead! Even though I'd miss the last train,
この恋に気づいてあたしにすればいいのに! PINKにだって染めるのに
realize this love and choose me! I'd even dye myself pink.
どうかあの子がいったい魅力に気づかないまま大人になりますように
May she remain unaware of your charm as she grows into an adult.
君の恋を応援できない あたしもこのまま大人になんなくて
I can't support your romance, and I won't grow up either.
性格悪いいいかな 噂はまだかな 振り向いてくれるのかな
Am I being mean? Are there rumors yet? Will you turn around and look at me?
友達からでいい 2秒だけでもいい ねぇ届いて
Friends is fine, just two seconds is fine, hey, reach him.
ピンクになってよ全然いいじゃん! 両手にピースでハイ・ハッピー
Turn pink, it's totally fine! Peace in both hands, high and happy!
飛んでけ周知心 持ってけ白昼夢
Fly away, common sense; take away, daydream!
ピンクになってよ全然いいじゃん! 誰もしゃべんないで
Turn pink, it's totally fine! No one say a word!
え、オリジナル曲ってスペシャル曲って、フルメドレーでした！イエーイ！
The original and special songs were a full medley! Yay!
え、今歌った最後の曲はですね、本日リリースした、夜空メルさんとによる「ピンクになっちゃえ」という曲なんですけれども、
The last song we just sang is "Pink ni Nacchae" by Yozora Mel, released today,
え、このステージ、そしてみんなの手元もちょっとピンクに染め上げさせていただいただいたところで、えっ！？ちょっと待って！
and since we've dyed this stage and everyone's hands a bit pink... wait, hold on!
えー！みんな知らなかったの？えー！全然知らなかった！
Eh?! Everyone didn't know? Eh?! We didn't know at all!
ということでね、ここで今夜からの超超超重大なお知らせをさせていただこうと思います！いえーい！
So, we'd like to make a super-duper major announcement starting tonight! Yay!
ですがね、告知後に全員で もう一曲歌いますので… え？そうだったの？知らなかった！
But after the announcement, we're all going to sing one more song... Eh? Is that so? We didn't know!
全然何も知らないよ！
We don't know anything at all!
ということでお話し、皆さん、最後までチャンネルはそのまま見ていってくださいねー！それでは！
So everyone, please keep watching the channel right to the end! See you!
こちらを、ご覧ください！
Please take a look at this!
特報
[Breaking News]
え、まず、オリジナル曲を作りたい！
First off, I want to make an original song!
なんと！博衣こより初めての…
And what do you know? Hakui Koyori's very first...
FIRST STEPのその先へ どうだったかな？
How was it beyond the FIRST STEP?
冬には いっぱい、いっぱい、夢がある
In winter, there are so many dreams,
全ての夢を叶えるのが夢 叶えていけるように
So that I can make all my dreams come true.
夢のソロライブに、みんなを連れて行きたい！
I want to take everyone to my dream solo live!
博衣こより 1st Live 開催決定
Hakui Koyori 1st Live Announced
2026.12.22 TOKYO GARDEN THEATER
Hakui Koyori 1st Live Dream Spark+
はーい、ということで、2026年12月22日、
So, on December 22nd, 2026,
東京ガーデンシアターにて、博衣こよりファーストライブ、「Dream Spark」の開催が決定いたしましたーー！
at Tokyo Garden Theater, Hakui Koyori's 1st Live "Dream Spark" has been decided!
やっほーー！やったーー！
Yay! We did it!
ついに夢の1つであるソロライブが決まりました！ありがとうございます！
Finally, my dream of a solo live has come true! Thank you so much!
今年できるとは思っていなかったので、みんなもちょっとびっくりしてると思うんですけれど、
I didn't think I could do it this year, so you're probably all a bit surprised, but
精いっぱい頑張っていくので、応援よろしくお願いします！
I'll do my absolute best, so your support would be greatly appreciated!
そして今回のライブのハッシュタグは、「＃夢煌めけこより」となっております。ぜひこちらでつぶやいてください。
And the hashtag for this live is "#YumeKiramekeKoyori". Please tweet with it!
ちなみにセカンドアルバムのハッシュタグも同じ「＃夢煌めけこより」でやっていくので、どんどんポストしていただけると嬉しいです！
Also, the 2nd album hashtag will be the same "#YumeKiramekeKoyori", so I'd be happy if you keep posting!
ライブの詳しい情報については後日発表予定となります。皆さんまずは12月22日、にゃんにゃんの日、ぜひ予定をあけて待っててください！
Detailed info will be announced later. Everyone, please clear your schedule for December 22nd!
そしてさらに、こよりのセカンドアルバム、「Chemical Spark」が12月2日に発売決定となりました！
And furthermore, Koyori's 2nd album, "Chemical Spark", will be released on December 2nd!
今回はホロライブオフィシャルショップ限定販売の完全生産限定盤と、こより初の全国流通での販売もある通常版の2種類となります。
There will be two editions: a Complete Limited Edition and a Regular Edition.
アルバムには書き下ろしの新曲のほか、CD限定の曲もありますので、ぜひともお聞きください！
The album features new songs and CD-only tracks, so please check it out!
まずは完全生産限定盤の同梱物についてご紹介します。こちらです！アルバムのイラストを使ったアクリルスタンドやホロかのほか、こよりからの想いを込めたお手紙、
First, the Complete Limited Edition. It includes an acrylic stand, Holoca, and a heartfelt letter from Koyori,
そして、直筆で皆さんにサインを書いたアナザージャケットがついてきます！
and an another jacket with a handwritten signature!
とっても豪華な六角形、このね、こよりの頭についているベニゼンカンと同じ形のスペシャルボックスパッケージとなっております！お楽しみに！
It's a gorgeous hexagonal special box shaped just like the hairpin on Koyori's head! Look forward to it!
さらに、なんと完全生産限定盤の予約特典として、先ほど発表したソロライブの先行抽選シリアルコードがついてまいります！
Plus, it includes a serial code for advance lottery ticket sales of the solo live!
シリアルコードはご注文1件に1つ付きますが、複数購入しても応募で使えるコードは1つだけなのでご注意ください！
Only one code can be used per order, so please be careful!
はい、そしてこちらが通常盤の同梱物です。
And here are the contents of the Regular Edition.
初回プレス限定で、全5種類のランダムアナザージャケットが1枚入っています！これはファーストアルバムと同じ形にさせていただきました。
It includes a random another jacket from a total of 5 types as a first-press bonus!
それぞれ違ったイラストレーターさんにイラストを描き下ろしていただいておりますよ！
They were newly illustrated by completely different illustrators!
今宵の直筆サインが入っているかもしれない
There might be a hand-signed autograph included tonight.
当たったらラッキーということで、おみくじ感覚でご予約ください。
If you win, consider it a lucky draw and pre-order yours!
そして、店舗さんでの特典アイテムはこのようになっております。ドンッ！
And here are the special store-specific bonus items! Ta-da!
それぞれ素敵なアイテムをご用意い……、ご用意いただきました！
They have prepared... they've prepared wonderful items for each store!
そして、なんとですね、秋葉原ゲーマーズ本店さんでリリースイベントを2025年1月8日に開催いたします！
And what's more, a release event will be held at the Akihabara Gamers main store on January 8, 2025!
ゲーマーズさんでCDをご予約・購入すると抽選に応募できますので
If you pre-order or purchase the CD at Gamers, you can enter a raffle,
詳細はゲーマーズさんのウェブサイトをチェックしてみてください。
so please check the Gamers website for details.
ちなみに先ほど披露したアルバムにも収録される桃鈴ねねさん作の新曲「ピンクになっちゃえ！」のMVをこのライブ終了後にプレミア公開させていただきますので、ぜひ見ていってください！
Also included in the album we performed earlier, Nene Momosuzu's new song "Pink ni Nacchae!" MV will premiere right after this live, so please check it out!
桃鈴ねねさんといつも一緒にやっている1032さんに1032さん節のMVを作っていただいてますので見てください！
1032-san, who always works with Nene Momosuzu, made a signature 1032-style MV for it, so please watch!
以上、アルバムはこの後21時より予約開始です。ご注目ください！
That's all. Album pre-orders start tonight at 9 PM. Please check it out!
さらに、実はもう一つ重大告知がございまして……ドドン！
Furthermore, there's actually one more major announcement... Ta-da!
TOKYO FMさんにて、10月に1ヶ月限定の特別番組の放送が決定いたしました！イェーイ！
A one-month special radio broadcast on TOKYO FM starting in October has been decided! Yay!
大好きなラジオ、そして冠番組がよく聞いていたTOKYO FMさんできるのがすごく嬉しいです！ありがとうございます！
I'm so happy to be able to do my favorite thing—a radio show with my own title on TOKYO FM, which I've listened to so much! Thank you!
応援日和などは後日発表させていただきますのでお楽しみに！
Support dates and other details will be announced at a later date, so look forward to it!
告知は以上となります。皆さん大変お待たせしました！ありがとうございます！
That's all for the announcements. Thank you all so much for waiting! Thank you!
すみません。
Sorry.
大丈夫、大丈夫。楽しみ待っていていただいて、ありがとうございます。
It's okay, it's okay. Thank you for looking forward to it.
じゃあ、ちょっと元に戻ってね。
Now, let's get back to normal positions.
はい、ということでお届けしました、holoAcousticLive第2回だったんですけども。
Yes, that was #holoAcousticLive Vol. 2.
この後ね、もう1曲歌うんでみなさんちょっと待ってくださいね。みんなで歌いますからね！
After this, we'll sing one more song, so everyone please wait. We'll all sing together!
はい、じゃあちょっと皆さんに1人ずつ感想とか、もしなんか告知とかあったらしていってください。ではLamyさん！
Now, let's hear your impressions one by one, or any announcements if you have them. Lamy-san!
いやあの本当こんな1番の後輩が言わせてもらうのもあれなんですけども、
Well, even though I'm the junior here saying this,
なんかもうKoyori先輩の本当頑張り屋さんのところがもういろんなところから感じられて、
I could feel Koyori-senpai's hard-working spirit from all kinds of places.
なんか最初さ、Towa様がさ、その歌詞のこと言ってたじゃん。
At first, Towa-sama mentioned something about the lyrics, right?
いや笑っちゃうわとか思ってたら、なんかそこにも感動してきちゃって。
and thinking "I'm gonna laugh," but then I ended up getting emotional about that too.
怒っちゃうの？
You're gonna get mad?
いや、怒っちゃうは本当に、ごめんごめん、笑っちゃうの。
No, "getting mad" is—sorry sorry, "laughing."
怒って笑っていいんだよ。本当にあの、
You can get mad or laugh, it's fine. Truly,
こんな素敵なライブに参加させてもらえたこと、そして重大発表も本当におめでとうございます！
I'm so glad to have participated in such a wonderful live, and huge congratulations on the major announcements!
おめでとうございます。またぜひ参加させてください。
Congratulations. Please let me participate again.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
じゃあ、Kobo-chan！
Next, Kobo-chan!
私は、えっと、Secondアルバムおめでとう！
I'm... um, congratulations on your second album!
うん、センキュー。で、Firstソロライブおめでとう！
Yeah, thank you. And congratulations on your first solo live!
おめでとう、ありがとう！
Congratulations, thank you!
で、私歌うのが好き。
And I love singing.
だから、ここは嬉しい。嬉しい！
So I'm happy here. I'm so happy!
ジェストに、呼んでくれて、呼んでくれてありがとう！
Thank you for inviting me as a guest!
呼んでくれて、ありがとう！
Thank you for inviting me!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
欲しいもの、何でもいいのよ。高いもの！
Anything you want, whatever you like. Something expensive!
高いものでもいいのよ。高いもの、オッケー？オッケー！
Even expensive things are fine. Expensive stuff, okay? Okay!
マンション！
A mansion!
マンション？マンションは無理、マンション！
A mansion? A mansion is impossible, a mansion!
やめろ、ニコ、やめろ。後でね。
Stop it, Niko, stop it. Later.
後でね、何でもいいのよ。はい、ありがとうね、本当に！
Later, whatever you want. Yeah, thank you so much!
ありがとう！また歌おうね。いつでも、いつでも本当？じゃあ、歌っちゃうよ！やった、ありがとう！
Thank you! Let's sing again. Anytime, anytime really? Then I'll sing! Yay, thank you!
とてもかわいい、ありがとう！
So cute, thank you!
そして、Towa様！
And, Towa-sama!
あのね、みんなと歌えたのがすごい嬉しかったです、まずは。
Well, first of all, I was so happy to be able to sing with everyone.
で、あとね、やっぱりあのニコも言ってたけど、こよりがね、ま、色々いろんな企画とかで、あの絡むことというか、ね。
And also, as Niko said, Koyori has been involved in various projects and things, you know.
一緒にやることがあるんですけども、なんか1つ1つのものにね、本当にね、全力投球というか。
We get to work together, and I've seen behind the scenes how she puts her all into literally everything.
はい、一生懸命頑張ってるのを裏でも見てきてたんで、本当にね、ソロライブできて、本当に、おめでとう！
Seeing how hard she works behind the scenes, I'm truly so happy she pulled off her solo live. Congratulations!
おめでとう！頑張ります、今日も！
Congratulations! I'll do my best today too!
はい、今日も頑張ってます、みなさん！
Yes, everyone's working hard today too!
褒めてあげてください、こよりちゃんのことを。
Please praise Koyori-chan.
頑張ります！もっと頑張ります！
I'll do my best! I'll work even harder!
緊張しました、今日も。ソロライブまで大変だったかもしれないけど、全力でまた頑張ってくださいね。ありがとうございます、先輩！はい、先輩です！
I was nervous today. It might have been tough leading up to the solo live, but please keep doing your best with all your might. Thank you, senpai! Yes, senpai!
はい、えー、まずはソロライブ開催と、えっと、アルバム発売、おめでとうございます！
Yes, um, first of all, congratulations on holding the solo live and releasing the album!
いや、本当に、もうこよちゃんはもう1...
Truly, Koyo-chan is...
なんか、なんばい頑張っていいたんだっていうぐらい
Like, we've worked so hard, you know,
本当に努力を 多分いっぱいいしてきて
putting in so much effort,
今日があって、なんかあのもうティザーで泣きそうになりましたよ。
leading up to today, and honestly, the teaser almost made me cry.
本当だよね、わかるわかる、泣きそうになるっていうか、
Truly! I know right, almost crying,
これが全部今につながって、今日があるし
realizing that all of this connects to today,
これからもっと忙しくなると思いますけど、みんなにいっぱい夢を与えてくださいね！
and while things will only get busier from here, please give everyone lots of dreams!
はい！いま、今日ありがとうございました！
Yes! Thank you so much for today!
ありがとうごさいましたー！また是非第3回もね！
Thank you so much! Please let's have a 3rd time too!
ちょっとちょっと、さ、さすがに、なんか、ちょっとおこがましいかなと
Wait a second, isn't that a bit presumptuous,
思いながら、あの、一緒にやってるみたいな気持ちになって、勝手に、あの、ありがとうございます！
thinking that while feeling like we're doing this together, so um, thank you so much!
いつもいつもお世話になってます。ありがとうございます！
We're always in your care. Thank you so much!
はい、ということでね、今日はちょっと緊張しすぎたし、あの発散しすぎで息切れしましたし
Yes, so today we were a bit too nervous, and got so excited we ran out of breath,
ちょっと恥ずかしい。私は、自分は本当は恥ずかしかったんですけれども、みんなと一緒に歌えたこの場がとっても楽しくて、幸せでございました！本当にありがとうございます！
how embarrassing. I was actually really embarrassed, but singing together with everyone in this space was so fun and happy! Thank you so much!
はい！この後も、え、商談いたしますので、ぜひお見守りください。よろしくお願いいたします！
Yes! There's business talks after this too, so please watch over us. Thank you very much!
はい！
Yes!
それでは、えー、なんか、お知らせとか大丈夫ですか？
Well then, um, are announcements and stuff okay?
いいですよ、いいですよ。なんかつぎ自分のあなたが主役の、そうそう
Sure, sure. Since you're the main character, right right.
それじゃあ、チャンネル登録をしてください。よろしくお願いします！この後枠もありますので、よろしくお願いします！
Well then, please subscribe to the channel. Thank you very much! There's an after-stream too, so please look forward to it!
それじゃあ、最後にちょっと一緒に歌わせていただきます！
Well then, lastly, we'll sing together!
はい！では、はい、では最後にお聞きください。
Yes! Now then, please listen to the final song.
ああ、ブライトパレード！
"Our Bright Parade"!
パレパレパレ 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade, shining bright,
呼び合う声を合図に
taking the calling voices as our signal.
パレパレパレ 探しに行く
Parade, parade, parade, going to search,
スタートは何回だって
starting over no matter how many times.
ただ ひとりごとつづった
Just stringing my soliloquies together,
ただ 始まり たくて走った
I just wanted it to begin, so I ran.
遠く 暗がりにともった
Lit up far away in the darkness,
それは 眩しすぎたのまえ
that was a blinding prelude.
それは 優しすぎた思い出
That was too gentle a memory,
もっと 近づけた手を伸ばした
I reached out a hand to get even closer.
思いがけないすれ違った ほら 今 迷い子は僕らになった
Unexpected thoughts crossed paths—look, now we've become lost children.
パレパレパレ 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade, shining bright,
悔しさも愛しさも連れておいで
bringing both our frustrations and our affections.
風よ 夢跳ね飛び立たせるさ
Wind, make our dreams leap and take flight!
ささやかな祈りは光 終わりだけ気付き
A modest prayer is light, noticing only the end,
君を見つけたこと 胸を張るよ
I'll hold my head high that I found you.
ここからここから
From here, from here,
あ、ブライトパレード！
Our Bright Parade!
まだ 頼りない予感を
Still trusting this unreliable hunch,
歌おう 恥ずかしくなんてないよ
let's sing, there's nothing to be embarrassed about.
誰も泣けない街なら
If it's a town where no one can cry,
いつか また会えるおまじない
a spell to meet again someday.
あの日 手の平に始まってずっと
Starting in the palm of our hands that day, and continuing forever,
数えきれないことの は 数えるような思い出じゃないさ
the countless things aren't memories you just count on one hand.
ほら 今 僕らのひとつとよぼう
Look, now let's call them our single dream.
パレパレパレ 美しいんだよ
Parade, parade, parade, it's so beautiful,
許し合える切な夜はきらめく
nights of forgiving each other sparkle.
雨晴れ晴れまたとな空
Rain, clear, clear, once again in the sky—
ふさわしいステージとは キミと歩くことさ
A fitting stage is walking together with you.
キミと歩くことなんだ
It is walking together with you.
ただいまを聞けば おかえりって叫ぶよ
If I hear "I'm home," I'll shout "Welcome back!"
当たり前じゃないか
Isn't that obvious?
パレード パレード パレード
Parade, parade, parade!
輝くんだよ
It shines bright!
暗がりを満たすのは キミだ ボクだ
What fills the darkness is you and me.
パレード パレード パレード 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade, shining bright!
悔しさも愛しさも 連れて おいで
Bring both frustration and love along.
風 夢 跳ね 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, wings, we can take flight!
ささやかな祈りは 光
Our modest prayers are light.
終わりなき兆し キミと飛び込んでゆく 素敵なスタートさ
An endless omen, diving in with you, a wonderful start!
ここから これから Our Bright Parade パレード パレード
From here, from now on, Our Bright Parade, parade, parade!
Our Bright Parade パレード パレード
Our Bright Parade, parade, parade!
Our Bright Parade!